CURRICULUM VITAE

Eng. Jonathan Ronoh

P. O. Box 42681 - 00100, Nairobi, Kenya

Mobile Number: +254727231171; +254788533988

Email Addresses: Jonathan.ronoh@erc.go.ke; Ronyeg2001@gmail.com

Personal Full Name Ronoh Jonathan

Details Nationality: Kenyan

National ID Number: 20030136

Date of Birth: 20th December 1977

Gender: Male
Marital Status: Married
Home County Kericho

Career Profile I am a very ambitious and resourceful electrical and electronic engineer

who can maintain big picture thinking and develop major business development strategies while attending to the details of operational

processes.

I have got over fifteen years of work experience in the energy and telecommunication sectors and my main areas of areas of expertise and interest include: power system operations, electrical installation works,

and design and implementation of telecommunication systems.

Education Jan 2010 to Aug 2012:

University of Nairobi

Master of Science in Information Systems.

Apr 2008 to Sept 2009:

Kenya Institute of Management Diploma in Business Management.

Oct 1997 to Nov 2002:

University of Nairobi

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronic Engineering

1992 to 1995: Cheborge High School (KCSE B+).

1984 to 1991: Korongoi Primary School

Professional Certifications

- Certified Information Security Manager (CISM)
- Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)

Short Courses Attended

Engineering / Energy Related Training:

- 19th 30th November 2018: Training on *Power System Operations* held at the National Power Training Institute in Bangalore, India.
- 6th 17th November 2017: Advanced Training Course: "Deployment of renewable energy solutions: challenges and opportunities", Milan Italy.
- 12th 16th December 2016: Training on *Protection of Electrical Power Systems* held at The Faradays Centre in Middleborough, UK.
- 29th 31st August 2016: Training on Wheeling Framework Agreement and Cross Border Power Trade by NARUC under sponsorship of USAID (Power Africa).
- 23rd 26th May 2016: Training on *PPA Review and Approval Process* conducted by NARUC under sponsorship of USAID (Power Africa).
- 30th November 11th December 2016 Training on *Power Systems Planning and Simulation* held at the Kenya Power Training School.
- 10th 16th April 2016: *Substation Engineering Course* conducted at Trans-Africa Projects (Pty) Ltd /Eskom in Midrand, South Africa.
- 2nd 20th May 2016: Training on *Electrical Distribution Systems Operations Course* conducted at Kafue Gorge Regional Training Centre (KGRTC) in Kafue, Zambia.
- 23rd 27th November 2015: One-week Workshop on *Scaling up of Solar Photovoltaics* held in Florianopolis Brazil (sponsored by GIZ).
- June- August 2005 (Two Months): *Telecommunication Engineer Training* conducted by Huawei in Shenzhen China.

Leadership and Project Management Training:

- Two weeks' leadership and change management course conducted by ESAMI in Pretoria, South Africa.
- One-year Diploma in Business Management (KIM).
- Three weeks course on project formulation and feasibility study analysis conducted by ESAMI in Arusha, Tanzania.

Professional Membership

- Registered as a Professional Electrical Engineer by the Engineers Board of Kenya (Reg. No A2912).
- Corporate Member of the Institution of Engineers of Kenya (IEK); (Mem. No M.3548)
- A member of ISACA International and Kenya Chapter (ID: 798467)

Work Experience

Energy Regulatory Commission (13 Years of Service)

Position: Principal Electricity Officer

Period: July 2018 to date. **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Participate in the development and review of regulations, codes and standards for electric power generation, transmission, distribution and metering.
- Examining and approving meters used or intended to be used for ascertaining the quantity of energy in collaboration with other government agencies;
- Undertaking research on and develop regulations and standards for meters and metering;
- Conduct written and oral interview for electricians and electrical contractors;
- Monitor technical performance of licensees including tracking of the supply and demand situation so as to enhance adequacy and reliability of the power system;
- Using power system performance data to generate accurate and timely executive reports to support decision making;
- Conduct periodic technical audits of power utilities and investigation of accidents and incidents;
- Participate in generation, transmission and distribution system planning and monitoring implementation of committed projects in the electricity subsector;
- Supervise staff in the department including completing performance appraisals, personal development and succession plans effectively, and on time in accordance with the established performance management system;
- Participate in the development of departmental budget and ensure efficient management of resources; and
- Represent the Commission in some external meetings, events and technical committees.

Position: Senior Technical Officer, Monitoring and Compliance

Period: Sept 2015 to June 2018 **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Coordinate the implementation of the ERC SCADA Project.
- Participate in the development and review of regulations, codes and standards for electric power generation, transmission, distribution and metering.
- Conduct written and oral interview for electricians and electrical contractors;
- Monitor technical performance of licensees including tracking of the supply and demand situation so as to enhance adequacy and reliability of the power system;
- Using power system performance data to generate accurate and timely executive reports to support decision making;
- Conduct periodic technical audits of power utilities and investigation of accidents and incidents;
- Participate in generation, transmission and distribution system planning and monitoring implementation of committed projects in the electricity subsector;
- Supervise staff in the department including completing performance appraisals, personal development and succession plans effectively, and on time in accordance with the established performance management system;
- Participate in the development of departmental budget and ensure efficient management of resources; and
- Represent the Commission in some external meetings, events and technical committees.

Jul 2008 - Sept 2015: Information Technology Administrator

Jan 2007 - Jun 2008: Assistant Information Systems Administrator

Duties and responsibilities: -

- Participate in the preparation and implementation of departmental budget and work plan;
- Management of ICT projects;
- Systems, network and security administration;
- Monitor ICT trends to provide advice on timely replacement or upgrades;

- Implementation and monitoring of IT control and security policies;
- Preparation of ICT systems specifications and design documents for procurement purpose;
- Monitoring implementation of IT control and security policies; and
- Preparation of ICT systems specifications and design documents for procurement purposes.
- Maintenance of ICT systems' power supply infrastructure.
- Regular status and performance reporting.

Telkom Kenya Limited (2 Years and 6 Months of Service)

Position: Senior Systems Engineer

Period: July 2004 to December 2006

Roles and Responsibilities

- Supervision of ADSL Network Management Centre (NMC) technical team;
- Preparation and implementation of budget and work plan for the NMC unit;
- Design, implementation and management of telecommunication Projects;
- Install and maintain power supply systems for the telecommunication systems;
- Implementation of systems security policies and procedures;
- Carry out scheduled preventive maintenance of telecommunication infrastructure/systems and their associated power supply; and
- Regular status and performance reporting.

MicroLAN Kenya Limited (1 Year 9 Months of Service)

Position: Systems Support Engineer

Period: Oct 2002 to June 2004

Roles and Responsibilities

- Design and implementation of data-communication projects;
- Setup and configuration of computers and communication systems;
- Installation of uninterruptible power supplies (UPS) and Voltage regulators/stabilizers; and
- Preparation of tender proposals.

International Energy Technik (IET) - (2 Months)

Position: Trainee Engineer.

Period: Aug 2002 to Sept 2002 **Roles and responsibilities:**

- Installation of Motor Control Centers;
- Implementation of Siemens Industrial Control Systems projects; and
- Installation of Power Factor Correction (PFC) systems.

Hobbies

- Reading engineering and technology-related articles and books.
- Participating in sports such as athletics and watching other sports.
- Volunteer work and other social involvements.

Referees

1. Eng. Robert Korir

Projects Execution Manager, KenGen P.O Box 47936 - 00100 Nairobi

Mobile: +254722840208 Email: <u>rkorir@kengen.co.ke</u>

2. Eng. Buge Wasioya

Former Power Systems Manager (Retired) Energy Regulatory Commission.

Mobile: +254721573328

Email: buge.wasioya@gmail.com